<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! I&#39;m Huizi on We Are All Stardust</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi! I&#39;m Huizi on We Are All Stardust</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 10:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on the 4 noble truths</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-08-notes-on-4-nobel-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-09-08-notes-on-4-nobel-truths/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just started to study a course on Coursera called “Buddhism and Modern Psychology”. I find it very interesting. The purpose of the course is not all about religion, but rather with the help of buddhism and modern psychology, how to find happiness and peace in life.
The first topic is about the 4 noble truths:
the truth of suffering the cause of suffering the cessation of suffering the Noble Eightfold Path  Here are some points from the course that I find interesting:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Analysis 2 - Music I listen To</title>
      <link>/post/2020-09-02-spotify-analysis-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-09-02-spotify-analysis-2/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I downloaded the track features of the Beatles’ songs from Spotify web API, and did some basic mining on it. We looked at the keys the Beatles used most, happiest songs, most danceable songs, the distribution of happiness and liveness of each album. It was fun stuff!
In this new post, I’m going to explore a little more. Not the Beatles though, today I’m going to take a look at my own listening habits!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Analysis 1 - the Beatles</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-25-spotify-analysis-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-08-25-spotify-analysis-1/</guid>
      <description>I absolutely love music! Spotify is my go-to app when I want to enjoy some listening. As someone who’s passionate about mining data and discover the story underneath, what’s great is that for each song, Spotify stores a list of its features such as acousticness, danceability, energy and more. Also, thanks to the {spotifyr} package by Charlie Thompson, we can easily use a web API by Spotify from which I can download very interesting data and play with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts after reading the Little Prince</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-22-the-little-prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-08-22-the-little-prince/</guid>
      <description>The Little Prince is one of my favorite books as a kid.
The writer meets a little prince when his plane crashed into Sahara, and the little prince is from a planet far away. He has a rose that he really loves and takes care of, while a fox wants to be tamed by him. These are the two little stories in the book that touches my heart the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you! Please send me a message if you have any thoughts or suggestions, or just to say Hi! Just fill out the form below and I will get back to you!
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>